我们不是顾念所见的
"We look not at what can be seen,
而是顾念所不见的
but we look at what cannot be seen.
因为所见的是暂时的
For what can be seen is temporary...
而所不见的是永远的
but what cannot be seen is eternal.
我们原知道 我们所居这地上的帐棚若被拆毁
For we know that if the earthly tent we live in is destroyed,
必将得神所造
we have a building from God,
不是人手所造
a house not made with hands,
在天堂永存的房屋
eternal in the heavens."
她本来要跟我一起走
She was gonna come with me.
有多远
How far?
在弗吉尼亚州的里士满城外
Outside Richmond, Virginia.
那里很安全
It was secure.
那里有围墙 房屋 20个人
It has a wall, homes, 20 people.
贝丝本想跟他一起走
Beth wanted to go with him.
她想送他去那里
She wanted to get him there.
虽然路途遥远 但如果行得通
It's a long trip, but if it works out,
这会是我们最后一次长途跋涉
it's the last long trip we have to make.
要是那里已经沦陷了呢
And what if it isn't around anymore?
那我们就继续前进
Then we keep going.
找一个新的安身之地
Then we find a new place.
(南卡罗来纳州)
现在更好了
It's better now.
《行尸走肉》
还有多远
How far out?
五英里
Five miles.
卡萝尔
Hey, Carol.
我在
I'm here.
已经走了一半的路程 我想试试通话距离
We're halfway there. Just wanted to check the range.
大家精神还不错
Everybody's holding tight.
五百英里都走过了
We've made it 500 miles.
也许这次很容易
Maybe this can be the easy part.
那是我们应得的
Got to think we're due.
我们20分钟后回话
Give us 20 minutes to check in.
如果没有回话 我们就去找你
We don't hear from you, we'll come looking.
收到
Copy that.
我一直都想告诉你一件事
I've been wanting to tell you something.
什么事
What's that?
交易
The trade.
那么做是正确的
It was the right play.
也起了作用 确实起作用了
It worked. It did work.
只不过之后发生了别的事
Just something else happened after.
该发生的总会发生
It went the way it had to.
该发生的终会发生
The way it was always going to.
我之前从未想杀人
I never wanted to kill anybody before.
我想杀人
I've wanted that.
但也只是为了
But it just made it
让我看不到我不想看到的事
so I didn't see anything except what I wanted.
我没有正视它
I wasn't facing it.
正视什么
Facing what?
过去的事 现在的情况
What happened, what's going on.
我父亲总是告诉萨沙和我
My dad always told Sasha and me
我们作为世界公民 有责任
that it was our duty as citizens of the world
了解新闻
to keep up with the news.
我小时候坐着他的车
When I was little and I was in his car,
广播里总会放那些新闻
there were always those stories on the radio.
一千英里外发生的
Something happens 1,000 miles away
或者我们街区发生的
or down the block.
我听都不敢听的恐怖事
Some kind of horror I couldn't even wrap my head around.
但他不换台
But he didn't change the channel.
也不关掉
He didn't turn it off.
他就一直听
He just kept listening.
正视它
To face it.
睁开双眼
Keeping your eyes open.
我父亲总是称之为
My dad always called that
活着要付出的高昂代价
paying the high cost of living.
我父亲在亚特兰大去世了
I lost my dad in Atlanta.
我觉得他会喜欢你爸爸的
I think he would have liked yours.
我妈妈和一对孪生兄弟还在
Still got a mom and a couple of twin brothers.
我希望他们没事
I hope.
我也希望
I hope so, too.
还有两英里就到了
Two more miles.
好的
All right.
在林子里停下 我们步行
Let's pull into the woods. We'll go on foot.
避开大路
Stay off the road.
没有这个必要
We don't need to.
以防万一
Just in case.
挺好的
This is good.
从林子外看 就像汽车残骸之一
Through the trees, it might just look like part of the wreck.
这边走
It's this way.
这些是你们的人设下的吗
Your people do this?
他们以前想设 一定是设好了
Wanted to. They must have.
你没事吧
You all right?
没事 没事
Yeah. Yeah.
你们有侦查员 狙击手吗
They have spotters? Snipers?
我们在一辆卡车上建了一个哨台
We built a perch on a truck.
有时停在大门外
Sometimes it's out front.
(夏尔维尔特住宅区)
今天没在
Not today.
你听见了吗
You hear that?
等我一下
Just wait.
诺亚 等等
Noah, hold up.
诺亚
Noah!
好了 没事的
Come on. It's all right.
你以后和我们一起
You're gonna be with us now.
我去解决
I'll get him.
我很遗憾 诺亚
I'm sorry, Noah.
真心的
I truly am.
我们找点能用的东西就往回走
We should see if there's anything we can use and head back.
然后呢
Then what?
它们发现我们了
They see us.
我们可以快速扫荡一番
We can make a quick sweep.
我在这里陪他
I'll stay with him.
卡萝尔 收到了吗
Carol, you copy?
收到了
We're here.
我们到了
We made it.
这里沦陷了
It's gone.
(克拉夫特伍德)
干净的上衣
Clean shirt.
- 我们会想出办法的 - 我们会的
- We'll figure it out. - We will.
车库里有几个垃圾袋
There's some garbage bags in the garage.
你没想到这里会沦陷吗
You didn't think it would still be here?
那你呢
Did you?
事情发生之后
After it happened,
就在贝丝在医院被杀之后
right after with Beth in the hospital,
我看见那个女人道恩
I saw that woman Dawn.
她不是故意的 我知道 我看见了
She didn't mean to do it. I knew it. I saw it.
但是我想杀死她
But I wanted to kill her.
我还记得我当时在想 杀她或者不杀
I remember I just wondered if it even mattered
有那么重要吗
one way or another.
跟贝丝一点关系都没有
Didn't have a thing to do with Beth.
我不清楚我到底相不相信这里还在
I don't know if I thought it would still be here.
但是贝丝想把他带到这里
But Beth wanted to get him here.
她想让他回家
She wanted to get him back home.
我们来这里是为了她
This was for her.
没准我们也可以住在这里
And it could have been for us, too.
我想要为我失去的一切
I wanted to die for what I lost.
和爱人去死
Who I had lost.
我走到一群行尸当中
I stepped out into a crowd of those things
想要…
just trying to...
用它们来泄气
take it all out on them
直到它们杀了我
until they took me.
让它们挡在面前 这样我就能逃避现实
Put them all in front of me so I didn't see anything.
但是
But
我还是继续前进了 所以之后
I just kept going. And then later,
当朱迪思需要我的时候我就在她身边
I was there for Judith when she needed me.
我救了她
I saved her.
送她回到爸爸身边
I brought her back to her dad.
如果我放弃了 一切都不会发生了
And that wouldn't have happened if I had just given up...
如果我没有选择继续活下去
If I hadn't chosen to live.
诺亚
Noah.
这并不是终点
This isn't the end.
你能行
There you go.
这就对了
That's right.
(避暑地)
我们应该…
We should...
诺亚
Noah.
Noah!
我一直在想终点站集装箱里的
I was thinking about that guy in the storage container,
那个人
back at Terminus.
我是怎么让大家停下的
How I made us stop.
离开监狱之后
After the prison,
在旅途中
on my trip,
我又见到了玛姬
I got Maggie back.
事情都还说得过去
Things went okay.
失去了华盛顿这个目标
Losing Washington...
失去了…
losing...
失去了贝丝
losing Beth
刚知道她还活着就失去了她…
right after just finding out she's alive...
那时我还没赶上你们
I hadn't caught up with you yet.
如果换做现在
If it were now,
我不会让大家停下的
I wouldn't make us stop.
我们会径直走过
We'd run right by.
而且我会打死那个女人
And I would have shot that woman dead.
管他对错呢
Right or wrong.
我们必须停下
We need to stop.
不然会在外面待太久的
You can be out here too long.
这是我家
This is my house.
- 你最好别进去 - 我要进去
- You don't want to go in there. - Yes, I do.
让我看看吧
Let me see it.
我打头阵
Me first.
我努力尽快赶回来了
I tried to come back sooner.
我努力了
I tried.
我按照你的话做了
I did what you told me to.
你没事的 坚持住 我去叫他们
You're okay. Just hold on. I'll get them.
我去叫他们
I'll get... I'll get them.
至少68名共和国公民
At least 68 citizens of The Republic
在对沿海主要地区的
have been killed in four deadly attacks
四次致命袭击中被杀
along the main coastal district.
叛军依然在滥用暴力
The group has continued their campaign of random violence,
肆意地穿过乡村
moving across the countryside unfettered
而共和国军一片混乱
with The Republic's military forces in disarray.
我告诉过你
I tried to tell you.
我告诉过你 伙计
I tried to tell you, man.
死的会是你
It was gonna be you.
你是舍身救婴儿的那种人
You're the kind of guy who saves babies.
你觉得如果你爆了我的头
You think Gareth would have been able to follow you guys
葛瑞还能追踪到你们吗
if you'd have just put a bullet in my brain?
或者像你妹妹一样砍死我
Cut me up like your sister did?
冷静 别起来
Oh, whoa, whoa. Don't get up.
如果我没告诉他们你在哪里
If I hadn't told them that you were there,
也许葛瑞就不会去找你
maybe Gareth wouldn't have gone after you.
也许他们就不会死
Maybe they wouldn't be dead.
也许鲍勃就不会死
Maybe Bob wouldn't be dead.
说不定他还活着
Maybe him being alive,
假如是这样的话
maybe something about that
可能贝丝的结局就会不同
would have changed things with Beth.
多米诺骨牌效应
Domino shit.
也可能不会
Maybe not.
也许你现在就不会被咬了
Maybe you wouldn't be bit right now.
伙计 那是胡扯
Man, that is bullshit.
我是在食品银行被咬的
I got bit at the food bank.
该发生的总会发生
It went the way it had to,
该发生的终会发生
the way it was always going to.
就像这次一样
Just like this.
…然后夜袭了村庄
...then terrorizing the village by night,
实施了报复行动
carrying out revenge attacks
其中包括用刀砍无辜人士
involving hacking innocents with machetes
以及用火烧某些无辜人士
and, in some cases, setting them on fire.
假如你杀了我
If you just did it,
假如你没有像个婊子一样撒谎
if you didn't lie like a bitch,
也许就会改变一些事情
it might changed things.
也许你就不用付出代价
Maybe the bill would have been paid.
必须付出代价
The bill has to be paid.
你必须证明自己的价值
You have to earn your keep.
你告诉过我 只要能留下来
You told me you'd do whatever you had to do
做什么都行
to earn your keep.
那是你的原话
That's what you said.
记得吗
Remember that?
现在更好了 泰尔西
It's better now, Tyreese.
真的
It is.
现在更好了
It's better now.
现在并没有更好
It's not better now.
你很清楚…
You know damn well what--
我们可以用几个车库门一起堵上缺口
We could put some of the garage doors together against the break.
停一辆车堵住它们 直到我们把墙修起来
Park a car against them until we can brick it back up.
能行的
It can work.
这地方被一片森林包围了
This place is surrounded by a forest.
视线不好
There's no sight lines.
不论是谁 或者什么东西
Whoever, whatever would
都可以神不知鬼不觉地袭击我们
be on top of us without us even knowing it.
那八成就是这里发生的事
That's probably what happened.
也是我们身上发生的事
That's what happened to us.
我们可以从砍树开始
We could start taking down the trees.
我们用树来建墙
We use them to build the walls up.
看着
Look.
不重要了
It doesn't matter.
什么
What?
你说你想过
You said you wondered if
杀不杀她到底重不重要
it even mattered if you killed her or not.
无论是你杀了她 还是我或达里尔杀了她
It doesn't matter if you had done it or if I had,
都不重要了
or that Daryl did.
不重要了
It doesn't matter.
华盛顿
Washington.
尤金在阻止灾变这件事上撒了谎
Eugene lied about a cure,
但是他想到华盛顿是有原因的
but he thought of Washington for a reason.
但他是在撒谎啊
But he was lying.
在阻止灾变上撒了谎
About the cure,
但是他仔细盘算过 并且意识到
but he did the math and realized that
华盛顿的生存机会最大
Washington was the place where there'd be a chance.
我们离那里很近
We're close.
假如那里有幸存者呢
What if there are people there?
假如那里有安全区呢
What if it's someplace that we can be safe?
我们离那里只有一百英里
We're 100 miles away.
这是个机遇 是个机会
It's a possibility. It's a chance.
而不像现在这样在外漂泊
Instead of just being out here.
勉强生存
Instead of just making it.
因为目前看来就是这样的
Because right now, this is what making it looks like.
难道你不想带着希望多活一天吗
Don't you want one more day with a chance?
我们该走了
We should go.
只有一百英里远
It's 100 miles away.
我们该去华盛顿了
We should go to Washington.
瑞克
Rick!
救命 瑞克 格伦 米琼恩
Help, Rick! Glenn! Michonne!
救命
Help!
诺亚 坚持住
Noah, hold on!
我来干掉它
I got him.
你没事吧
You okay?
- 是泰尔西 - 在哪儿
- It's Tyreese! - Where?
我家 他被咬了
My house. He's been bit.
?每个人都有生存的权利?
?Every man has a right to live?
?爱是我们所拥有的一切?
?Love is all that we have to give?
?我们为了生存一起奋斗?
?Together we struggle by our will to survive?
?我们为了幸存一起拼搏?
?And together we'll fight just to stay alive?
?奋斗之人 必须前行?
?Struggling man has got to move?
?奋斗之人 时不我待?
?Struggling man, no time to lose?
?我是个奋斗之人?
?I'm a struggling man?
?而我必须前行?
?And I've got to move on?
没事了 泰尔西
It's okay, Tyreese.
你现在应该懂了
You gotta know that now.
你不想继续参与也没事 泰
It's okay that you didn't want to be a part of it anymore, Ty.
你没必要非得参与
You don't have to be a part of it.
看吧 这就是你的问题了
See, that's your problem right there.
我有什么问题
What's my problem?
你不想参与其中
You didn't want to be part of it,
但活着就是参与
but being part of it is being now.
就是这样
That's what it is.
睁眼看清楚吧
Open your eyes.
你没必要参与 如果你不想参与的话
You don't have to. Not if you don't want to.
真的没必要 现在这样更好
You don't. It's better now.
你说你会证明你的价值
You told me you'd earn your keep.
你那时候不知道自己在说什么 对吧
You had no idea what you were talking about, did you?
对吧
Did you?!
你睁着眼睛 却不想去看清现实
Your eyes were open, but you didn't want to see.
即便我早就逼你去看了
Even though I made you see it.
我都给你看了
I showed you.
但你听进去了吗
But did you adapt?
你改变了吗
Did you change?
没有
No.
你却坐在一个
That you would sit there in front of a woman
杀了你爱人的女人面前
who killed someone you loved...
你原谅了她
and you would forgive her.
就是这样
That's all there is.
就是这样了
This is all there is.
你完了
This is it.
我不知道我在跟谁说话
I didn't know who I was talking to.
我说了只要能留下来 我做什么都行
I said I would do what I had to to earn my keep,
但我不知道你的真面目
but I didn't know you.
但我知道
But I know--
我知道我是谁
I know who I am.
我知道过去发生了什么 现在又是什么情况
I know what happened and what's going on.
我知道
I know.
你什么都没给我看
You didn't show me shit.
你 你已经死了
You, you're dead.
你曾经的一切
Everything that you were
都已经死了
is dead.
一切…
And it's--
一切还没结束
it's not over.
我原谅她是因为
I forgave her because...
一切都还没结束
it's not over.
一切都没结束
It's not over.
一切 一切都没结束
It's-- it's not over.
我没有逃避现实
I didn't turn away.
我一直在听新闻
I kept listening to the news
这样我就能尽我所能去帮忙
so I could do what I could to help!
我不会放弃
I'm not giving up.
你听到了吗
You hear me?
我不会放弃
I'm not giving up!
像我这样的人
People like me--
像我这样的人 他们能活下来
people like me, they can live.
今天任何人都不会死
Ain't nobody got to die today.
你必须付出代价
You have to pay the bill.
- 你按住他 - 好了 上
- You hold him! - I got it! Go!
一刀 干净利落 砍
One hit, clean! Go!
用力
Push it!
快走 快走
Let's go! Let's go!
- 快走 - 从后面走
- Let's go! - Through the back.
得把锁链砸断
We've got to break the chain.
走
Let's go.
- 我们用球棒 - 我扶他
- We can use the bat. - I got him.
你能把他扶住吗
Can you hold him up?
可以
Yeah.
准备好
Get ready!
一二三 起
One, two, three, now!
伙计 假如你真这么想
Man, if you believe that,
那死的人一定是你和那个小孩
then it's definitely gonna be you and the kid.
- 不 - 别管了
- No-- - Leave it.
我扶着他 保持清醒 保持清醒
I got him. Stay with us, now. Stay with us.
你必须付出代价
You have to pay the bill!
我扶着你 慢点 慢点
I got you. Easy now, easy.
好的 一二三
Okay, one, two, three.
什么 等等
What? Wait, wait, wait, wait!
- 快点 - 快点
- Come on! - Come on.
睁眼
Open them!
拜托老兄 睁开眼睛 睁开眼睛
Come on, man. Open your eyes. Open your eyes!
该发生的总会发生
It went the way it had to,
该发生的终会发生
the way it was always going to.
你必须坚持住 坚持住
You got to hold on, man. Hold on!
- 抬他的腿 - 二 三
- His feet! Get his feet. - Two, three...
我们走
Let's go!
快 把他递给我
Come on, give him to me.
- 抬他进来 - 我扶住了
- Bring him in. - I got him.
- 扶他坐起来 - 你没事的 你没事的
- Hold him up. - You're all right. You're all right.
卡萝尔 我们上车了
Carol, we're at the car.
我们需要灼烧和包扎伤口
We need to cauterize the arm and wrap it.
支走萨沙和卡尔
Get Sasha and Carl away.
他们没必要看到这个
They don't need to see this.
快点 快点
Come on, come on, come on, come on.
快啊 快啊
Come on. Come on!
据报道 在共和国交通走廊
There have been troubling reports of cannibalism
附近的难民营出现了
having broken out in refugee camps
令人不安的食人现象
along the republic's transportation corridor.
尽管叛军取得了一系列胜利
And despite the string of victories by rebel forces,
但是有报告显示他们的战术愈发残忍
there are disturbing reports of increasing the brutality of their tactics
包括对村庄的大规模破坏
including the wholesale destruction of villages,
烧毁当地监狱 伤害平民
burning down local prisons, targeting of civilians,
甚至将孩子和年轻母亲断肢
and even the widespread mutilation of children and young mothers.
而这看起来只是
And this seems like only the beginning
他们所谓的无尽战争的开始…
of their campaign that they label as an endless war against...
关掉
Turn it off.
你确定吗
You sure?
没事了 泰尔西
It's okay, Tyreese.
你现在应该懂了
You gotta know that now.
不仅仅是没事了
It isn't just okay.
现在更好了
It's better now.
我们不是顾念所见的
"We look not at what can be seen,
而是顾念所不见的
but we look at what cannot be seen.
因为所见的是暂时的
For what can be seen is temporary,
所不见的是永远的
but what cannot be seen is eternal.
我们原知道 我们这地上的帐棚若拆毁了
For we know that if the earthly tent we live in is destroyed,
必将得神所造
we have a building from God,
不是人手所造
a house not made from hands,
在天堂永存的房屋
eternal in the heavens.
在天堂
In the heavens."